welcome back to another darktable
欢迎回到另一张暗桌
tutorial in this video we're going to be
在这段视频中 我们将成为
learning about how to use some of the
了解如何使用一些
more common modules in darktable for
暗表中更常见的模块用于
applying effects and edits to raw images
对原始图像应用效果和编辑
this will also work for images that are
这也适用于以下图像
not raw images if you don't have some so
不是原始图像 如果你没有这样的图像
I've downloaded a couple different ones
我已经下载了几个不同的
here and I got them from we saturate
这里和我从我们饱和的地方拿到的
dot-com I'll include the link in the
我会把这个链接放在
description this video it's just a free
描述：这段视频是免费的
website you have to sign up but it's
你必须注册的网站 但它是
free and it's not the it's just public
这不是免费的 它只是公开的
domain artists photographers sharing
领域艺术家摄影师分享
their images with other people and so
他们与他人的形象 所以
you click on an image and then you can
你点击一张图片 然后你就可以
download the raw version in some cases
在某些情况下下载原始版本
not all of them but you can download the
不是全部 但您可以下载
jpg or the raw version and then you can
JPG或原始版本 然后您可以
edit that image and so not all of them
编辑该图像 因此不是所有图像
have an option for raw but a lot of them
可以选择生的 但很多都是
do and there's just some pretty cool
就会有一些很酷的东西
images so here's one that doesn't let
所以这里有一个不会让
you download the raw so just make sure
你下载原始的 所以只要确保
if you want to get a raw image you can
如果你想得到一个原始图像 你可以
do some searches through here and
在这里做一些搜索 然后
there's some really good high-quality
有一些非常好的高质量的
there are pretty large image sizes too
也有相当大的图像尺寸
but anyway that's we saturate com
但不管怎样 这是我们饱和的COM
and that's where I got these from
这就是我从那里得到这些的
include the links for these also but you
也包括这些链接 但您
can see they're different file
可以看到它们是不同的文件
extensions too for raw so any fdn GCR to
RAW的扩展名也是如此 因此任何FDN GCR到
ARW so depending on what camera you're
啊 这取决于你用的是什么相机
shooting with it has a different format
用它拍摄有不同的格式
for raw but since darktable is amazing
对于生食 但因为暗表是令人惊叹的
it can interpret all of those and it
它可以解释所有这些 而且它
knows how to read all types of RAW files
知道如何读取所有类型的原始文件
so what we can do is we can either drag
所以我们能做的是 我们可以拖拽
and drop these in we can select them all
把这些放进去 我们可以把它们全选出来
and drag all of them in or we can just
把他们都拖进来 或者我们可以
go over here under import and go to
转到此处的IMPORT下并转到
folder and just import the entire folder
文件夹并只导入整个文件夹
so I'll just go select that folder and
所以我会选择那个文件夹 然后
go to open and now they're all imported
打开 现在它们都是进口的
in here into darktable
在这里进入暗台
let's apply some modules and do some
让我们应用一些模块并做一些
edits to this picture here I'm going to
对这张图片的编辑我将在这里
double click on it to bring it into the
双击它以将其带到
darkroom and we can quickly jump between
暗室和我们可以快速跳跃在
any of those ones if we look here across
其中任何一个 如果我们从这里看过去
the bottom we can double click and
在底部我们可以双击并
quickly jump into any of the ones that
快速跳转到任何一个
are in our light table without actually
都在我们的灯光桌上 而实际上
having to go into light table to grab
不得不走进轻桌去抓取
them and so when we're in darkroom we
所以当我们在暗室里的时候
can do that we can just double click but
可以做到这一点 我们只需双击
let's do this one here just because the
让我们在这里做这个 只是因为
rest of these are already so perfect and
其余的都已经很完美了
they look so great already that I'll
它们看起来已经很棒了 我会
probably do is end up
可能做的就是结束
making them look worse so this one we
让他们看起来更糟所以这一次我们
can that we can do some improvements on
我们能在这方面做些改进吗？
so we see that it's sort of dark this
所以我们看到这里有点暗
looks like one maybe you just like take
看起来像一个 也许你只是喜欢拿
on your phone we can see what this was
在你的手机上我们可以看到这是什么
taken on by clicking the image
点击图片即可
information so this was taken with a
信息 所以这是用一个
Sony camera but a lot of times pictures
索尼相机但很多时候都是照片
you'll just take quickly you're gonna
你要抓紧时间 你要
look like this it's not exposed very
看起来像这样 它不是很暴露
well the sky is really bright and so
天空真的很亮 所以
everything else is really dark we want
其他的一切都是我们想要的黑暗
to try and bring out some of the detail
试着带出一些细节
again I'm not really experienced in
再说一次 我在这方面没有什么经验
doing this type of color correction but
正在做这种颜色校正 但是
I just want to get to show you some of
我只是想给你们展示一些
the modules that I think are good to
我认为很好的模块
start with there's a lot of different
首先 有很多不同的
directions we could take this but we see
我们可以走这条路 但我们看到
what's happened already we have the
已经发生了什么 我们有
original we have some sharpening that's
原来我们有一些锋利的东西 那是
happened and then this base curve has
发生了 然后这条基本曲线
been applied and so the base curve we
已经被应用 所以我们的基本曲线
could get in and adjust but I wouldn't
可以进入并调整 但我不会
recommend it unless it looks really bad
推荐它 除非它看起来真的很糟糕
so bad would be like let's just reset
太糟糕了 就像我们重启
this to default so if it hasn't the
这是默认的 所以如果它没有
default base curve it might look really
默认基本曲线它看起来可能真的
dark like this we could click and make
像这样的黑暗 我们可以点击并制作
our own base curve and see if we can
我们自己的基本曲线 看看我们能不能
make this look a little bit better which
让这个看起来更好一点
maybe we can look at that just by doing
也许我们可以通过这样做来看看
this we can make it look caning that
这个我们可以让它看起来像是在鞭打
looks not too bad
看起来还不错
you know if we want to see what it would
你知道 如果我们想看看会发生什么
look like well what should we do maybe
看起来是这样的 也许我们应该做些什么
we'll just leave this well let's leave
我们就走吧 好吧 我们走吧
this base curve right here okay so we've
这条基本曲线 好的 所以我们有
got our base curve adjusted or we could
调整我们的基本曲线 或者我们可以
use the one that it had which was this
使用它所拥有的那个 也就是这个
sony alpha like but it looks like this
索尼Alpha一样 但它看起来像这样
particular image it's sometimes it's
特定的形象有时是这样的
better to to adjust the curve a little
最好是稍微调整一下曲线
differently than it had so let's go back
与以前不同 所以让我们回到过去
to that base curve we had because we
我们的基本曲线 因为我们
were rocking it so this is our own
我们在摇摆 所以这是我们自己的
little base curve that we created and
我们创建的一条基本曲线
now let's go to sometimes I like to do
现在让我们来看看有时我喜欢做什么
you've probably seen I do exposure a lot
你可能见过我经常曝光
so let's go to the exposure and it's
所以让我们去曝光吧 它是
good just to look at this histogram up
只要向上看这个直方图就好了
here this is just telling us to the far
在这里 这只是在告诉我们远方
left is black pixels to the far right is
左边是黑色像素 最右边是
white pixels so and this this is all of
白色像素 这是所有的
our data this is kind of a chart of all
我们的数据这是一张图表
of the pixels in our in our image from
我们的图像中的像素
left to right we see a dip in the middle
从左到右 我们看到中间有一个凹陷
here and that's because like this dark
这里和那里是因为像这样的黑暗
area is everything here that was
面积是这里曾经的一切
really kind of darker and this light
真的有点暗 这道光
area is all the sky and this middle is
区域是整个天空 中间是
going to be stuff that's sort of it by
将会是某种程度上的东西
gray is kind of in the middle so it's
格雷在中间 所以它是
not really having to do much with color
不需要对颜色做太多的事情
although the color is overlaid behind
虽然颜色是覆盖在后面的
you can see but really this is going to
你可以看到 但实际上这将是
be a chart of our light and dark pixels
是我们明亮和黑暗像素的图表
in the in the image we don't want the
在图像中 我们不希望
this data to ever go off to the left or
这些数据会向左或向左移动
to the right and that's what exposure
向右 这就是曝光的内容
adjusts is the left and right of this
调整是这个的左侧和右侧
histogram so we can see if we if dragged
柱状图 这样我们就可以看到我们是否被拖拽了
this we can squeeze it all up tight and
这样我们就可以把它挤得紧紧的
so everything is gonna be starting at
所以一切都将从
medium gray and going towards bright
中灰色 走向明亮
that's why everything looks kind of
这就是为什么所有东西看起来都像是
weird and if we drag this back or the
奇怪的是 如果我们把这个拖回去或者
other direction we're stretching it off
在另一个方向 我们正在把它拉开
so half our chart is now over here and
所以我们图表的一半现在在这里
we can't even see it so everything that
我们甚至看不到它 所以一切
was there all that detail is now just
有没有所有的细节现在只是
black we don't want that either but it's
黑色 我们也不想要 但它是
a good idea let's go back to this button
好主意 让我们回到这个按钮
here will let us reset it to how it was
在这里让我们把它重置到原来的样子
so there's a little bit you can see in
所以你可以看到有一点
here if i zoom in way close there's a
在这里 如果我放大到很近的地方 有一个
little bit of space in there where
在那里有一点空间
there's this white area and then there's
这是一个白色区域 然后是
off-the-chart so the chart has some
在图表之外 图表中有一些
space that could go we're gonna drag
我们要拖拽的空间可能会消失
this and you can even use the mouse the
这样 您甚至可以使用鼠标
scroll wheel to get a really fine and
滚动滚轮以获得一个非常精细的
tune that so we're gonna drag this right
把它调好 这样我们就能把这首歌
here so that it's about just starting
在这里 这只是一个开始
off of there then the other side we're
离开那里 然后我们在另一边
gonna do the same thing we're gonna drag
会做同样的事情 我们会拖着
this just so that the the detail is
这只是为了让细节
right to the bottom there that's what I
就在那里 我就是这么想的
like to do with exposure is fill this
喜欢曝光的就是填满这个
all in without clipping any of it the
在没有任何剪裁的情况下都加入了
detail we can check this little button
详细信息 我们可以查看这个小按钮
down here if we click this this is our
在这里 如果我们点击这里 这是我们的
under an overexposed indicator so we
在过度曝光的指示器下 所以我们
just see parts of the sky is overexposed
只需看到天空的一部分被过度曝光
and anything that would be in blue would
任何蓝色的东西都会
be really underexposed areas and
是真正曝光不足的区域
anything that is in red would be
任何红色的东西都会是
overexposed areas so that's okay right
曝光过多的区域 所以没问题 对吧？
there right I mean we could if we want
就在那里 我的意思是 如果我们想的话
to really keep that detail we kind of
为了真正保持这种细节 我们有点
have no blue and no red showing but I
没有蓝色和红色的显示 但我
think I'll leave that right there we'll
我想我会把它留在那里我们会
toggle this off
将其关闭
so that's exposure a little bit playing
所以这就是曝光的一小部分
with that is a good first thing to do
有了这一点 我们首先要做的就是
with your image then also levels is
与你的形象 那么也是水平
going to be a good thing too and levels
也会是一件好事 而且水平很高
is over
已经结束了
here in the tone group so we click on
在音调组中 我们点击
this and again if we hover over it tells
一次又一次 如果我们悬停在上面 它就会告诉我们
us what these groups are so we were in
我们知道这些团体是什么 所以我们在
the basic group now let's go to we did
基本小组现在让我们来看看我们做过的
exposure now let's go to tone group and
现在让我们进入音调组
let's change the levels a little bit
让我们稍微改变一下级别
since we played with exposure we don't
既然我们玩了暴露游戏 我们就不会
want to start adjust this endpoint at
要在以下位置开始调整此终结点
out point this is kind of the same thing
我要说的是 这差不多是一回事
black over here white over here and then
黑的在这里 白的在这里 然后
the middle adjusts how the Grays are not
中间派调整了灰熊队的不同
necessarily the greys
必然是灰人
but the mids mids are displayed because
但显示MIDs MIDs是因为
it's it's kind of weird with color and I
这是一种奇怪的颜色和我
don't even understand it exactly but
我甚至不能完全理解它 但是
this is adjusting all the kind of the
这是在调整所有类型的
mid-tones so we can drag this and sort
中间色调 这样我们就可以拖动它并进行排序
of bring out some more color here and
在这里展现出更多的色彩
it's sort of shifting the way this chart
这在某种程度上改变了这张图表的方式
looks but then we can come in and adjust
看起来是这样 但之后我们就可以调整了
that a little bit now we've kind of lost
现在我们有点迷失了
some detail in the sky it looks like
天空中的一些细节看起来像是
though but that's okay because really we
不过 没关系 因为我们真的
can adjust that in a little bit here so
我可以在这里稍微调整一下 所以
I want to see the detail here which
我想看看这里的细节
we've actually made a big difference
我们实际上已经做出了很大的改变
already to how it was before this that
已经到了这之前的样子
was before this is how it looks now and
是在这之前 现在看起来是这样
again we've talked in the last video
我们在上一段视频中又谈到了
real quick but let's just do this for
很快 但我们就这么做吧
fun we can create a snapshot so if we go
有趣的是 我们可以创建快照 所以如果我们去
to our original and we expand this
到我们的原始版本 然后我们扩展这个
snapshot over here this is one that I
快照在这里 这是我
took earlier we can we don't want that
早点拍的 我们可以 我们不想那样
to be there we'll just click this to get
要到达那里 我们只需点击此处即可获得
rid of it click take snapshot will
将其清除 单击拍摄快照将
always take a snapshot of whatever your
始终为您的
image looks like currently in the dark
图像目前看起来像是在黑暗中
room and then now we have the snapshot
空间 现在我们有了快照
let's go back and start editing and we
让我们回去开始编辑 我们
can enable this by clicking on it let's
可以通过点击来启用它 让我们
click on it and now we can see here we
点击它 现在我们可以在这里看到我们
can see what our changes look like so
可以看到我们的更改是什么样子的
this is before and this is after so
这是之前的 这是之后的
really cool that's looking good we'll
真的很酷 看起来不错 我们会
just keep it off to the left hand side
只要把它放在左边就行了
right now while we're making changes and
现在 我们正在做改变
whenever we want we can just drag and
无论何时我们想要我们都可以拖着
kind of overlay and see how it's looking
有点重叠 看看它是什么样子
ok and we can do it from before too we
好的 我们也可以从以前开始做 我们
could take a snapshot at the exposure
可以在曝光时拍摄一张快照
level take snapshot and then we can go
水平拍摄快照 然后我们就可以走了
to that one and then we conceded the
然后我们就承认了
difference how it looked just at that
光是看上去就不一样
exposure level that make sense so this
有意义的暴露水平 所以这
is the difference between 5 & 6 between
5和6之间的差值是
these two different edits between
这两个不同的编辑
exposure and the levels changes we made
曝光量和我们所做的水平变化
so then we can see just what exactly did
那么我们就可以知道到底是什么
the levels do did it improve
这些水平确实提高了吗？
or did it hurt the quality of our image
还是说它损害了我们的形象质量
and we see it's a little bit lighter up
我们看到它稍微亮了一点
there like on the roof and stuff anyway
就像屋顶上的东西一样
let's put this over here let's turn that
我们把这个放在这里 我们把那个
off for now and let's try to let's look
暂时离开 让我们试着去看看
at one more thing that's good to do just
还有一件事是值得做的
for like photos in general so white
喜欢的照片一般都是白色的
balance is something good we can adjust
平衡是我们可以调整的好东西
the temperature temperatures usually in
温度通常在
these like thousands of K if you ever
如果你曾经有过 这些就像是几千
look on like an LED light bulb or like
看起来像一个LED灯泡或类似的
just different things like the Sun has a
只是不同的东西 比如太阳有一个
certain light temperature and like the
一定的光温 就像
moon has a certain light temperature so
月亮有一定的光温 所以
suppose this was taken in the moonlight
假设这张照片是在月光下拍摄的
it might look more like this with a
它可能看起来更像是带有一个
lower temperature it looked more like
更低的温度看起来更像是
you have a lot more blue and the colors
你有更多的蓝色和颜色
would look differently because the light
看起来会不一样 因为光线
source is different so this temperature
来源不同 所以这个温度
kind of adjusts the with the light
一种用光来调节的
source so we want to we'll probably want
所以我们想要我们可能会想要
to match a certain way but if we have it
以某种方式匹配 但如果我们拥有它
go up higher see it it was at around
往上走 看看它是在什么地方
5,000 was it oh no one do that let's
是5000吗？哦 没人这么做 让我们
leave this on I think we can reset to
把这个开着 我想我们可以重置到
default how it was so it was down here
默认情况下 它就在这里
at 5,000 so maybe let's turn it up to
5000美元 所以让我们把它调高到
about 6,000 that was kind of cool and
大约6,000人 这很酷
have it more of a yellow look so all the
让它看起来更像黄色 所以所有的
Reds and the blues everything kinda has
红军和蓝军什么都有
is as if it has a more like a evening
就好像它有一个更像是一个夜晚
sunset on it so we'll leave that and we
日落在上面 所以我们把它留在那里 我们
could adjust colors individually if our
可以单独调整颜色 如果我们的
white balance was off the way to check
白平衡不在检查的范围内
that if you hit click your middle
如果你点击点击你的中间
control wheel you can zoom in and see
控制轮您可以放大并查看
this
这
so our whites are looking like they're
所以我们的白人看起来像是
being displayed pretty accurate I think
我认为展示得相当准确
I know it's hard to tell but it's easy
我知道这很难说 但很容易
to tell if you haven't really off
来判断你是否还没有真正离开
sometimes you'll have like a lot of
有时候你会有很多
they'll look like this or something
他们会看起来像这样或什么的
you'll have too much of a certain cover
你会有太多的特定掩护
too much red or too much green in your
太多的红色或太多的绿色
whites so you would adjust that by just
白色 所以你只需要调整一下
coming down and adjusting the this green
下来调整这个果岭
slider here let's reset that to how it
这里的滑块 让我们将其重置为
was is put the temperature back to 7006
是把温度调回7006度
thousand all right
一千美元 好的
there we go and now since we made a
我们走了 现在因为我们做了一个
bunch of changes over here we see if
这里有一大堆变化 我们看到
ever we have to like we have a base
我们必须永远喜欢我们有一个基地
curve happening twice we can get rid of
曲线发生两次 我们可以摆脱
that and kind of undo but we can
以及某种程度上的撤销 但我们可以
compress those into the same thing by
通过以下方式将它们压缩为相同的内容
clicking this compress history stack and
单击此压缩历史记录堆栈并
now those
现在那些
changes in the bass curve a bit and then
低音曲线稍有变化 然后
combined so look we're losing some
加在一起 看 我们正在失去一些
detail in our sky but what I think I
我们天空中的细节 但我想我
want to do with this we're gonna imply a
想要做到这一点 我们将暗示
vignette anyway and I'm going to change
无论如何 Vignette和我要改变
the sky before I do that let's see if we
在我这样做之前 让我们看看我们是否
can change the color of the sky so to do
可以改变天空的颜色这样做
that there's a couple different things
有几件不同的事情
we could do we've done we've looked a
我们可以做到我们已经做到了我们看起来
little bit at this in this color
在这个颜色里看一下这个
so this is our color group we can do a
这是我们的颜色组 我们可以做一个
color correction where we just change
颜色校正 我们只需更改
the color of everything in the picture
图片中所有东西的颜色
in general this sort of has a little bit
一般来说 这种类型有一点
of the same effect we were seeing with
与我们看到的相同的效果
the cover temperature that we just did
我们刚才所做的盖子温度
but here we're gonna adjust the color of
但在这里 我们要调整颜色
the sky but at the expense of also
天空 但代价也是
adjusting the color of all the pixels
调整所有像素的颜色
like look at the colors of the ground is
就像看着地面的颜色一样
changing too so if we want to adjust the
如果我们想要调整
sky without affecting this down here we
天空不会影响这下面的我们
don't want to use the color corrector so
我不想用色彩校正器 所以
I'm gonna reset that to default what we
我要将其重置为默认设置
want to use is this color lookup table
要用的是这个颜色查询表
it's down here under more modules so
它在下面的更多模块下 所以
this is a good one to do where's that
这是个不错的选择 那个在哪里？
adds I don't know if you do this on
我不知道你会不会这么做
every photo I passed it cover lookup
我给它的每一张照片都是封面查找
table a color lookup table is going to
表一个颜色查找表将被
let us choose a certain color you can
让我们为您选择一种您可以选择的颜色
also do this by brightness which might
也可以通过亮度来执行此操作 该亮度可能
make more sense in this case but let's
在这种情况下更有意义 但让我们
choose a certain color like what's
选择一种特定的颜色 比如
happening in the sky there so it's
发生在那里的天空 所以它
probably like these this gray will play
很可能像这样 这个灰色的将会演奏
more with this in the in other videos
有关这一点的更多信息 请参阅其他视频
but for the time being we select a color
但目前我们选择一种颜色
like the all of the this these this
就像这一切
color right now and then we can adjust
我们可以不时地调整颜色
just that color without affecting
就是那个颜色 不会影响
everything else but I want to make sure
除了我想要确保
this has some more Browns in it so I
这里面有更多的布朗 所以我
don't think it'll affect the ground too
不要认为这也会影响地面
much so look we can change this we can
所以听着 我们可以改变这一切 我们可以
add some more make it look more like
再加一些 让它看起来更像
blue and purple in the sky without
天空中没有蓝色和紫色
affecting everything else here so that's
影响到这里的其他一切 所以这是
kind of cool and then we can see the
有点酷 然后我们就可以看到
clouds a little bit more in there we can
在那里有更多的云 我们可以
adjust the lightness or darkness of it
调整它的亮度或暗度
so we can really make that sky look
所以我们真的可以让天空看起来
really cool without changing everything
在不改变一切的情况下真的很酷
else we're not we're not applying a
否则我们不会我们不会申请
color layer over top of everything we're
彩色层覆盖在我们的一切之上
just adjusting colors within this sort
只是在此排序中调整颜色
of white gray range this will make more
这将使更多的
sense as we play with it more in the
当我们在游戏中更多地玩它的时候
future but that looks pretty cool right
未来 但这看起来很酷 对吧？
so if we turn this off we
所以如果我们把它关掉
before really kind of flat and the sky
以前真的很平坦 天空
just makes everything look I know that
只会让一切看起来像我知道的
blue sky that's actually too much now
蔚蓝的天空 其实现在太多了
that I now that I really look at it
我现在我真的看着它
so we maybe adjust the we can adjust the
所以我们可以调整我们可以调整
saturation here so it's not quite so
这里是饱和的 所以并不完全是这样
intense but we can still give it that
强烈 但我们仍然可以给它
sort of a different look than the
看起来有点不同于
original photo had and maybe we'll just
原来的照片有了 也许我们就
let's apply our vignette and just stop
让我们施展我们的小插曲 停下来
right there we could bring out some more
就在那里 我们可以拿出更多
detail well let's do one more just so we
好的 让我们再做一次 这样我们就
can get a little bit experience with it
我可以从中获得一点经验
we can adjust the under here under the
我们可以在这里的下面调整一下
basic under the base or these basic
基础下的基础或这些基础
group we can go to shadows and
小组 我们可以去阴影和
highlights so these are always good to
突出显示 所以这些总是很好的
adjust to or a lot of times it can be to
适应或在很多时候可以适应
our advantage if ever there's some dark
我们的优势是 如果有一些黑暗
parts like here that we want to bring
像这里这样的部件 我们想带去
out or some of these shadows we can
或者这些阴影中的一些我们可以
adjust just the shadows here and just
只调整这里的阴影 然后
for fun let's suggest and see how that
为了好玩 让我们提出建议 看看如何
changes the look and feel of this image
更改此图像的外观
so we can sort of bring brighten up sort
所以我们可以把亮化的东西
of what's happening down here we don't
我们不知道下面发生了什么
want to do too much so it wasn't so bad
想要做得太多 所以不是那么糟糕
and the highlights is gonna adjust some
亮点将会调整一些
of these highlight pixels too so we can
其中的高亮像素 这样我们就可以
kind of give more detail into the sky
给天空赋予了更多细节
there and really see those clouds a lot
在那里 真的能经常看到那些云
but I don't know and then if we don't
但我不知道 如果我们不
want if we do it the other direction it
如果我们反其道而行之的话
kind of makes it like a glow maybe we
有点像是在发光 也许我们
will adjust that and keep those in there
会调整它 并把它们留在那里
a little bit that kind of looked cool
有点那样看起来很酷
with that detail so that's one two
有了这样的细节 这就是一二
that's that can be a lot of fun to play
那是玩起来会很有趣的
with the shadow and highlights and a lot
有阴影和高光以及很多
of pictures can benefit from this module
的图片可以从此模块中受益
as what as well let's apply one more
还有什么 让我们再来一个
module because this video is starting to
模块 因为这段视频开始
get kind of long I'm gonna do the
变得有点长 我要做
vignette which is going to be this very
Vignette将会是这样的
last one we have option for this
最后一次我们有这个选择
vignette
微晕
so the vignette what it lets us do it
所以它允许我们做的是什么
just puts draws a circle here there's
只要放在这里画一个圆圈就可以了
actually a outside circle as well we can
实际上 我们也可以在外面的圈子里
click on this little circle and move it
点击这个小圆圈并移动它
around and change the shape of it and if
并改变它的形状 如果
you hold your control wheel and scroll
你握住你的控制轮并滚动
well out you can zoom out so you can see
好了 你可以缩小 这样你就能看到
what's happening here what we want to do
这里正在发生的事情是我们想要做的
is wrap is put this around our
是把这个包裹在我们的
our subject or our focal point of the
我们的主题或我们的焦点
image so we're gonna put this right here
所以我们要把这个放在这里
we can move it by left-clicking and move
我们可以通过左键单击并移动来移动它
where it's at and we see this outer
它在哪里 我们看到这个外部
circle is feathering a dark sort of a
圆圈是一种黑色的羽毛
dark area see the corners now are sort
黑暗的区域看角落现在是排序的
of shadowy and dark whereas the center
阴影和黑暗 而中心
is bright so it's just applying sort of
是明亮的 所以它只是应用了一种
a mask overlay to make everything look a
遮罩覆盖 使一切看起来像
little bit more kind of draw your
更多一点吸引你的
attention to the center of this and so
注意这件事的中心
let's do that maybe right like that and
让我们这样做 也许是对的 然后
it depends on how extreme we want it
这取决于我们想要的极端程度
that's a little too extreme I think and
我觉得这有点太极端了
let's make this more oval like my
让我们把这个弄得更像我的椭圆形
computer's going kind of slow for some
对某些人来说 计算机运行得有点慢
reason right now I'm not sure what's
原因现在我不确定是什么
happening that's maybe that's okay yeah
如果发生了 也许这没什么 是的
so that's that's great there so now we
所以这很好 所以现在我们
can um let's come over here and hit and
我们能不能到这里来打一打
click on our compress history stack get
点击我们的压缩历史堆栈获取
all that history there and let's just do
所有的历史 我们就这么做吧
a quick walk through and see what what
快速浏览一下 看看有什么
all we've done I'm just a click on this
我们所做的一切我只是点击一下
what happened did it did I get rid of
发生什么事了？我摆脱了吗？
that oh I click on original okay so
哦 我点击了原创 好的 所以
we're gonna see what we've done here I'm
我们要看看我们在这里做了些什么
gonna hold down the control wheel zoom
会按住控制轮的变焦
this in so this is our original raw
所以这是我们的原始原料
picture that we downloaded we did a
我们下载的图片我们做了一个
little bit of sharpening we didn't do
我们没有做的一点磨砺
this this automatically happened the
这是自动发生的
orientation was unaffected and the base
方向未受影响 底座
curve we did play with us a little bit
曲线我们确实和我们一起玩了一会儿
remember so we made it look like this
记住 我们让它看起来像这样
with our base curve then we use the
使用我们的基本曲线 然后使用
exposure a module and we adjusted the
暴露了一个模块 我们调整了
exposure a little bit then we adjusted
曝光了一点 然后我们就调整了
the levels which is kind of a gonna gave
在某种程度上 这是一种将要给出的
it some more contrast between the light
光线之间的反差更大了
pixels and the dark pixels then we
像素和暗像素 然后我们
applied a white balance and in white
应用了白色平衡和白色
balance what we did was the temperature
平衡我们所做的是温度
so we adjusted the temperature to make
所以我们调整了温度以使
it look a little bit more warm that's
它看起来更暖和一点 那是
the only thing we adjusted there then we
我们在那里唯一调整的就是我们
did I don't think we we clicked on color
我是不是觉得我们我们选上了颜色
correction but we didn't really do
更正 但我们并没有真正做到
anything so it's we didn't really use
任何事情 所以我们并没有真正使用
that one but it's still in our history
那个 但它仍在我们的历史中
stack because we made changes and then
堆栈 因为我们进行了更改 然后
set it back to no changes we did this
将其设置为不更改我们做了此操作
color lookup table which is how we added
颜色查找表 这就是我们如何添加
some more blue color to the sky that
为天空增添更多的蓝色
really wasn't there originally but we
原本并不在那里 但我们
added in just for some effect and then
只是为了一些效果而加进去 然后
we adjusted shadows and highlights which
我们调整了阴影和高光
we probably could have done earlier on
我们很可能早些时候就做了
in our
在我们的
stack but we adjusted the shadows and
堆叠 但我们调整了阴影和
highlights to kind of gotta bring more
亮点一定会带来更多
attention to some of the detail in here
注意这里的一些细节
I guess and then we applied a vignette
我想 然后我们用了一个小插曲
to make us focus make the viewer focus
让我们聚焦让观众聚焦
more on what's happening here
更多关于这里正在发生的事情的信息
and so let's grab a snapshot of this
所以让我们来抓拍这个的快照
final one and then look back here enable
最后一个 然后回过头来启用
the final one and we can see our before
最后一张 我们可以看到我们之前的
and after this time before is on this
在这个时间之后 之前是在这个上面
side and after is here so that's pretty
Side and After在这里 所以很漂亮
cool right pretty cool stuff
很酷 对 很酷的东西
as a final thing so what you're gonna
作为最后一件事 所以你要做的是
want to do is export this so what let's
想要做的就是出口这个 所以让我们
because I did it reverse way we're
因为我反其道而行之我们是
clicking on our original now so if we go
现在点击我们的原件 所以如果我们去
back into light table it's going to look
回到明亮的桌子上 它将看起来
like there's no changes made to it so we
就像它没有任何变化一样 所以我们
need to go into darkroom and click on
需要进入暗室并点击
the highest level of our history stacked
我们历史的最高水平堆积在一起
if we want to export it like this and
如果我们想像这样出口它
then go to a back to our light table now
那么现在就去a背靠背我们的轻桌吧
we're seeing it with the changes so this
我们看到了它的变化 所以这个
looks like the way we want it to look
看起来就是我们想要的样子
and so to export this because it's not
所以要把这个出口 因为它不是
going to look like that on our computer
在我们的电脑上看起来会是这样
if we go back and find the raw file it's
如果我们回去找到原始文件
gonna be unchanged and just how it was
将会保持不变 就像以前一样
before anyway we have to export this so
在此之前 我们必须出口这个 所以
we can't just go to save there's no file
我们不能就这样去保存没有文件
save on the menu bar or anything what we
保存在菜单栏或任何我们
have to do is go to export selected and
要做的就是将所选内容导出并
then since this is a selected image
则由于这是选定的图像
there's only one we just click on export
只有一个我们只需点击导出
don't worry about changing anything in
不要担心更改任何内容
here for now and it's going to export it
目前在这里 它将输出它
to a folder called darktable
添加到名为Darktable的文件夹中
exported in the same directory as our
导出到与我们的
source image and our source image again
源映像和我们的源映像
is unaffected we didn't change our
不受影响我们没有改变我们的
source image at all instead we just
源图像而不是我们只是
exported it to this folder which is
已将其导出到此文件夹中
right here it created a new folder
就在这里 它创建了一个新文件夹
called darktable exporter that wasn't
被称为暗桌导出器 而不是
there before with our final image right
在此之前 我们的最终图像是正确的
here so that's kind of a workflow I kind
这就是我喜欢的一种工作流程
of wanted to demonstrate some of those
想要展示其中的一些
modules that you'll probably use when
您可能会在以下情况下使用的模块
working with a lot of things except
处理很多事情 除了
maybe not so much the color lookup but a
也许与其说是颜色查找 不如说是
lot of the rest of those are ones that
其余的很多都是
you'll use all the time in in darktable
你会用所有的时间在暗台上
so hopefully that kind of gave you a
所以希望这能给你一种
little bit more confidence using some of
使用以下几个选项更有信心
those there is no right and wrong way
那里没有对与错的路
just get in here and play
快进来玩吧
well there's probably some wrong ways
嗯 可能有一些错误的方式
but there's no right ways so just go
但没有正确的方法 所以你就走吧
ahead and just get in and play and see
在前面 只要进去玩一玩 看看
what different things do what are we and
什么不同的事情做什么我们是什么和
this is the vignette we could have
这是我们可以拥有的小插曲
adjusted some different things on the
调整了一些不同的东西
vignette and change that a little bit we
小插曲和改变一点我们
could have added a crop and you know
可以增加一种作物 你知道的
cropped in here so there's all kinds of
在这里裁剪 所以有各种各样的
different things look here's a bloom
不同的东西看起来这里是盛开的
what does bloom do what does sharpen do
布鲁姆做什么？锐化做什么？
just get in and play and figure it out
只要进去玩玩 想办法就行了
and you're gonna find some that you
你会找到一些你认为
really like to use a lot so and when you
真的很喜欢用很多所以当你
do add them to your favorites so you
一定要将它们添加到您的收藏夹中 这样您就可以
click here and just go ahead and click
点击此处 继续点击
the star to the side and then you'll
把星星移到一边 然后你就会
have a nice workflow of favorites that
有一个很好的收藏工作流
you do and the more you do it the more
你做的越多 你做的就越多
you're gonna get comfortable with using
你会习惯于使用
darktable
暗桌
and in the next tutorial or pretty soon
在下一篇教程中或很快
here we're gonna learn how to save some
在这里 我们将学习如何节省一些
of these presets so you can kind of save
这些预置 这样你就可以节省
and make your process much much quicker
让你的过程变得更快
when you're first starting out it's
当你刚开始的时候
going to be very time consuming and you
这将非常耗时 而你
can spend a lot of time you know hours
可以花很多时间 你知道 几个小时
on a single photo just tweaking and
在一张照片上 只是调整和
trying to get it right but yeah thanks
我试着去做正确的事 但还是谢谢
for watching guys leave your questions
因为看着男人们留下你的问题
or comments below and I'll catch you in
或者下面的评论 我会告诉你的
the next video
下一个视频